there's another side as many sides of
the psychedelic world and one side that
I know is a particular interest of yours
is the micro dosing side of psychic
herbs and micro dosing is where you take
a sub perceptual dose of your
psychedelics now people have different
attitudes about this so my first
question would be what are the dominant
attitudes that you see arising in the
culture about the use of micro dosing
different psychedelics yeah so one thing
is that you can't inspire the usual
population doing that because it's still
an illegal scheduled substance
absolutely there there might be some
risks induced and people's are will be
skeptical anyway so we are talking about
a psychedelic user population which is
already using these kind of things and I
think there are a lot of aspects about
that one is or one major aspect is that
you can take a psychedelic on a more
regular basis without having all these
irritating distracting effects and so
therefore a lot of people think oh I can
do LSD without getting as a risk of
being fragmented or getting on a horror
trip we're all getting a mystical
experience you know it's a kind of risk
minimization in the understanding of the
people that's one aspect another aspect
is that these substances might do
something to the human organism which
might be good even if we don't dose them
so much that we have these psychological
alterations is this it from a
pharmacological point and I'm a
pharmacologist to this might be possible
but this is there's up to now no
reliable AB evidence to my eyes that it
is really the case this is not that all
the reports are not true but they are
still anecdotal might have been placebo
induced and so on so we still don't know
exactly from a scientific point of view
if this is really a method which can
alter whatever kind of thing
like a creativity creative thinking
stuff like that what we know is you
can't other creative sinking or your
thoughts or your thought patterns if you
are not doing a dose which is uttering
your thought patterns if you use a dose
which is sub perceptual it means you
can't detect it and so you can't detect
changes in your thoughts so this is
beyond the definition what I would like
to introduce here is that when I have
written the recent book which I have
written about my as a science of micro
dosing I came across a kind of 50
studies in the past which have been done
with very low doses nobody knows about
that the whole internet is free of that
there is no knowledge and this is how
the Internet can generate illusions
because they people don't look at the
past anymore they are just in the now
which is mindful but maybe idiotic in
another sense that they ignore the past
and they don't know about and what we
know from these early studies is that
above 20 micrograms you get a certain
kind of effect which might in some rare
cases in behave in a way that people
might become a little more creative but
I would bet that because of individuals
and sative it is about the substance
even if he would those them within
quality known and purity known stuff and
could give everybody 20 micrograms or
let's say 30 or something they would
still have completely different
reactions somewhat and so therefore it's
very hard to dose in the real what I
call above 20 micrograms where you get
some kind of effect I would like to call
that mini dosing coming from 20 to 50
and a lot of the people which have micro
dosed in the past for example about
Huisman the discoverer of LSD has has
done in a more or less erratic fashion
let's say five to seven times a year at
maximum he did 30 to 90 milli
meet micrograms and that is quite a
different deal then you have some
effects it's not a full-blown experience
yes we know from recent research that
the full-blown LSD experience needs 200
micrograms then you have the full-blown
effects if you go lower you have less
effects it's not a bad thing it might be
even good but we still have to define
where what micro dosing in that sense is
yes it's really tough isn't it I mean
it's tough to get a grip on what the
full LSD experience would really be I
mean do you mean to refer to the peak
breakthrough mystical experience okay
you know no it's it's just that we know
from the question your profiles yes and
from clinical experience that you don't
get much more if you get a higher dose
and you get somewhat less if you take a
lower dose so we know that all the
responses on these questionnaires they
got maximum activated when you have that
kind of those and you got much less if
you get lower doses okay so but that
doesn't mean like with a car you can run
200 miles let's say with an sports car
but you usually run 50 right and so if
is if speed of fifty is much more usable
for you in the average day then running
200 you know you know what I'm talking
about yes right so it doesn't mean that
a hundred micrograms for example can do
a lot in respect to psychotherapeutic
processing which might you'd which might
be not as optimal with a full dose yes
and so therefore I'm not discriminating
lower dosages or something yes no
absolutely I mean it's it one thing for
me that other eye that I not quite
seeing as much in conversation about
psychedelics is really what the
fundamental aim is whether whether it's
for an individual's life or a collective
now people are talking